A bond. A pledge. A commitment.
Guy Ritchie's The Covenant is a war, action,
thriller film directed by Guy Ritchie.
During the war in Afghanistan, a local interpreter risks his own life to
carry an injured sergeant across miles of grueling terrain.
Master Sergeant John Kinley, played by Jake Gyllenhaal.
Ahmed, played by Dar Salim.
Charlie 'Jizzy' Crow, played by Sean Sagar.
Joshua 'JJ' Jung, played by Jason Wong.
Tom 'Tom Cat' Hancock, played by Rhys Yates.
Eduardo 'Chow Chow' Lopez, played by Christian Ochoa.
Guy Ritchie's The Covenant (or simply The Covenant) is a 2023 American action drama film
produced and directed by Guy Ritchie co-written with Marn Davies and Ivan Atkinson.
The film stars Jake Gyllenhaal and Dar Salim.
Its plot follows John Kinley, a U.S.
Army Green Beret Master Sergeant sent home after surviving a Taliban ambush and a harrowing trek to safety, and his
subsequent journey to rescue Ahmed, his Afghan interpreter, whom John feels indebted to for saving his life.
The film was theatrically released by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer and STXfilms in the United States on April
21, 2023, received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed $21 million.
The film explores themes of rescue, ambush, interpreter,
afghanistan, afghanistan war (2001-2021).
The tone is intense.